<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Post on Data Engineer, Consultant, BI Developer in MarTech</title>
    <link>http://andrewrgoss.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Post on Data Engineer, Consultant, BI Developer in MarTech</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://andrewrgoss.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>The Data Science Industry: Who Does What</title>
      <link>http://andrewrgoss.com/2016/the-data-science-industry-who-does-what/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>http://andrewrgoss.com/2016/the-data-science-industry-who-does-what/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Great infographic from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.datacamp.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;DataCamp&lt;/a&gt; that lays out the roles and skills associated with a data science team. I&amp;rsquo;m best cast as the data engineer right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://101.datascience.community/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/datasciencejobs.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;*Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.datacamp.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;DataCamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Udemy- Python for Data Structures &amp; Algorithms</title>
      <link>http://andrewrgoss.com/2016/udemy--python-for-data-structures--algorithms/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>http://andrewrgoss.com/2016/udemy--python-for-data-structures--algorithms/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/post/python.png&#34; alt=&#34;Python&#34; title=&#34;Python&#34; /&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.udemy.com/python-for-data-structures-algorithms-and-interviews/learn/v4&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;COURSE LINK&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://nbviewer.jupyter.org/github/jmportilla/Python-for-Algorithms--Data-Structures--and-Interviews/tree/master&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Jupyter Notebooks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
Working on furthering my Python skills in the following areas:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Algorithm Analysis and Big-O Notation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Array Sequences&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stacks Queues and Deques&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Linked Lists&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recursion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trees&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Searching and Sorting Algorithms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Graph Algorithms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jupyter Notebooks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, this course focuses on some of the &amp;lsquo;soft skills&amp;rsquo; needed to advance a career in technology such as personal branding, building a strong professional network, and practicing technical questions that could be asked on a future interview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;course-progress:ba96cbb6aafc41eabb6ce89e58c06fa0&#34;&gt;Course Progress&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;progress max=&#34;1.0&#34; value=&#34;0.21&#34;&gt;&lt;/progress&gt;

&lt;p&gt;21% - &lt;font color=&#34;green&#34;&gt;IN PROGRESS&lt;/font&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/andrewrgoss/udemy-python-data_structs-algorithms&#34; class=&#34;btn&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;View my code on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Data University- Hadoop 101</title>
      <link>http://andrewrgoss.com/2016/big-data-university--hadoop-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>http://andrewrgoss.com/2016/big-data-university--hadoop-101/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/post/hadoop.png&#34; alt=&#34;Hadoop&#34; title=&#34;Hadoop&#34; /&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Course Code&lt;/b&gt;: BD0111EN&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://bigdatauniversity.com/courses/introduction-to-hadoop&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Course Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://my.imdemocloud.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;IBM Analytics Demo Cloud&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/page/big_data_university_hadoop_101/lesson_transcripts&#34;&gt;Lesson Transcripts&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
Reinforcing some of the basics of Apache Hadoop, a free, open source, Java-based programming framework. Topics in this course include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hadoop&amp;rsquo;s architecture and core components, such as MapReduce and the Hadoop Distributed File System (HDFS).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adding/removing nodes from Hadoop clusters, how to check available disk space on each node, and how to modify configuration parameters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other Apache projects that are part of the Hadoop ecosystem, including Pig, Hive, HBase, ZooKeeper, Oozie, Sqoop, Flume, among others.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stages of the Analytics Life Cycle</title>
      <link>http://andrewrgoss.com/2016/stages-of-the-analytics-life-cycle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>http://andrewrgoss.com/2016/stages-of-the-analytics-life-cycle/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Across industries, the applied use of data to inform business decisions has become a foundational (arguably critical) element of business. The end goal is to ultimately derive actionable insights from vast amounts of data being collected but it takes a series of activities/tasks to arrive at this juncture. Here is a description of each stage of the analytics life cycle:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Data Acquisition&lt;/b&gt; – This may involve scraping data, interfacing with APIs, querying relational and non-relational databases, or defining strategy in relation to what data to pursue.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Data Cleaning/Transformation&lt;/b&gt; – This may involve parsing and aggregating messy, incomplete, and unstructured data sources to produce datasets that can be used in analytics and/or predictive modeling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Analytics&lt;/b&gt; – This involves statistical and machine learning-based modeling in order to understand, describe, or predict patterns in the data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Prescribing Actions&lt;/b&gt; – This involves interpreting analytical results through the lens of business priorities, and using data-driven insights to inform strategy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Programming/Automation&lt;/b&gt; – In many cases, data scientists are responsible for creating libraries and utilities to operationalize or simplify various stages of this process. Often, they will contribute production-level code for a firm’s data products.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;*Source: Burtch Works&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;big-data-analytics-lifecycle:fabfcdc15793a32766e038f5387cbc68&#34;&gt;Big Data Analytics Lifecycle&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Big Data analysis differs from traditional data analysis primarily due to the volume, velocity, and variety of characteristics for the data being processed. This is a helpful overview I found on the high-level steps involved with acquiring, processing, analyzing, and repurposing data with the end goal of performing Big Data analysis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.informit.com/content/images/chap3_9780134291079/elementLinks/03fig06.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;*Source: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.informit.com/articles/article.aspx?p=2473128&amp;seqNum=11&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;InformIT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Report- The State of Data Engineering</title>
      <link>http://andrewrgoss.com/2016/report--the-state-of-data-engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>http://andrewrgoss.com/2016/report--the-state-of-data-engineering/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently came across an excellent report by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.stitchdata.com&#34; target=_&gt;Stitch&lt;/a&gt; on the state of data engineering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, there are 6,500 people on LinkedIn who call themselves data engineers. In San Francisco alone, there are 6,600 job listings for this same title. The number of data engineers has doubled in the past year, but engineering leaders still find themselves faced with a significant shortage of data engineering talent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The need for data talent is born from a fundamental shift: tech companies are now data companies. Uber, AirBnB, Spotify–these companies build data products, and as a result, are scrambling to hire (and hold onto) the people that build and maintain data systems. Josh Wills, Data Engineer at Slack, half-joked, half-pleaded at DataEngConf 2016, &amp;ldquo;Please don&amp;rsquo;t hire my data engineers, they are all here now.&amp;rdquo; Even Slack, one of the hottest tech companies in the valley, is worried about holding onto this valuable talent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This report takes an in-depth look at the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The number of data engineers in the market today&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Their backgrounds and core skills—information that is particularly valuable for leaders thinking about how to transition software engineers into data engineering roles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Employment information that can help make the case for investing in this often expensive skill set.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Answers to these questions are paired with input from engineering leaders at Stripe, MIT, Looker, and more; who share their strategies for finding and retaining talent, developing data engineering talent in-house, and prioritizing a data engineering team&amp;rsquo;s projects. This report presents a clear snapshot of the current state of data engineering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.stitchdata.com/resources/reports/the-state-of-data-engineering&#34; class=&#34;btn&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;View the full report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;*Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.stitchdata.com&#34; target=_&gt;Stitch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SSH Keys With PuTTY and Cygwin for Windows</title>
      <link>http://andrewrgoss.com/2016/ssh-keys-with-putty-and-cygwin-for-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>http://andrewrgoss.com/2016/ssh-keys-with-putty-and-cygwin-for-windows/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.chiark.greenend.org.uk/~sgtatham/putty&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/post/putty.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;PuTTY: a free SSH and Telnet client&#34; title=&#34;PuTTY: a free SSH and Telnet client&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my work at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.digitaslbi.com/us&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;DigitasLBi&lt;/a&gt;, I need to login to a number of client-specific Linux machines via a terminal emulator (there is no UI for these remote environments) from my local Windows laptop. For this my team uses &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cygwin.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Cygwin&lt;/a&gt;, a Linux-like environment for Windows making it possible to port software running on POSIX systems (such as Linux, BSD, and Unix systems) to Windows. It&amp;rsquo;s possible to login of course just using a standard username/password combination with &lt;a href=&#34;https://mosh.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Mosh&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Secure_Shell&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;SSH&lt;/a&gt; at the command line. However, the more secure (and easier to manage) approach is to utilize SSH keys to login into a virtual private server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll delve into how I&amp;rsquo;ve set up my computer to use public/private SSH key pairings for accessing different environments. I previously &lt;a href=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/2016/ssh-with-git-bash-and-tortoisegit-for-windows&#34;&gt;posted&lt;/a&gt; about using SSH keys with Git Bash and TortoiseGit for Windows. While it&amp;rsquo;s possible to use the same SSH key pairings that were used for that, I prefer the more secure approach of generating specific pairings for &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Github&amp;nbsp;&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/github.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;https://about.gitlab.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Gitlab&amp;nbsp;&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/gitlab.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and any client-specific instances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-1:f77569a6b4afc10750083404d55c7c58&#34;&gt;Step 1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Download the following PuTTY files from this site: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.chiark.greenend.org.uk/~sgtatham/putty/download.html&#34;&gt;http://www.chiark.greenend.org.uk/~sgtatham/putty/download.html&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PuTTY (the SSH and Telnet client itself)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pageant (an SSH authentication agent for PuTTY, PSCP, PSFTP, and Plink)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PuTTYgen (an RSA and DSA key generation utility)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-2:f77569a6b4afc10750083404d55c7c58&#34;&gt;Step 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using the downloaded PuTTYgen executable, &lt;a href=&#34;https://winscp.net/eng/docs/ui_puttygen#generating_a_new_key&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;generate a new key&lt;/a&gt;. Click the &amp;lsquo;Save public key&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;Save private key&amp;rsquo; buttons to save these to the same location as your other keys (if you have any). On Windows, the .ssh folder of your home directory will be something like this: &lt;code&gt;C:\Users\\*username*\\.ssh&lt;/code&gt;. You can create this directory if it doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist. When saving the private key you will be optionally asked to enter a password for another layer of security if desired - it is also possible to hit &amp;lsquo;OK&amp;rsquo; and not use a password in combination with the SSH private key. Keep PuTTYgen open for now as you will need to copy the public key value into the authorized_keys files on the appropriate private server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/post/putty_gen.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;PuTTY Key Generator&#34; title=&#34;PuTTY Key Generator&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure you save the public key with a .txt (or .pub) extension and the private key with a .ppk one:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.servermom.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/public-key-save.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.servermom.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/private-key-saved.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-3:f77569a6b4afc10750083404d55c7c58&#34;&gt;Step 3&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open up Cygwin and log into the machine that you wish to configure with SSH keys. You&amp;rsquo;ll need the standard username/password credentials for the instance for now. In your home directory, issue the following commands:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;$ mkdir -p .ssh
$ chmod 700 .ssh
$ nano .ssh/authorized_keys
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Copy the generated public key in PuttyGen and paste it in the Nano editor:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.servermom.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/copy-pub-key.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Save and exit Nano by hitting &lt;code&gt;ctrl+O&lt;/code&gt;, enter, then &lt;code&gt;ctrl+X&lt;/code&gt; on your keyboard. Then change its permission to 644 with this command:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;$ chmod 644 .ssh/authorized_keys
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-4:f77569a6b4afc10750083404d55c7c58&#34;&gt;Step 4&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ensure that PuTTY&amp;rsquo;s Pageant (downloaded in Step 1) is running (you should see a little icon for it in the tray at the bottom of your screen):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://niki.hammler.net/w/images/f/f6/Pageant.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Double-click this to see the current list of private keys loaded to Pageant. You can manually load them each time through this UI when your computer boots up, but the more efficient approach is to have them load on startup following &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.shvetsov.com/2010/03/making-pageant-automatically-load-keys.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;these steps&lt;/a&gt;. Pageant can load one or more private keys when it starts up if you provide them on the Pageant command line. The simplest way to do this in Windows is to create a specially crafted shortcut inside the Startup folder (Start -&amp;gt; Programs -&amp;gt; Startup).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-5:f77569a6b4afc10750083404d55c7c58&#34;&gt;Step 5&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last step is to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/cuviper/ssh-pageant&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;download this daemon&lt;/a&gt; that allows you to use your loaded SSH keys from PuTTY&amp;rsquo;s Pageant in Cygwin. By editing your &lt;code&gt;~/.bashrc&lt;/code&gt; (or &lt;code&gt;~/.bash_profile&lt;/code&gt; - check where Cygwin is installed on your computer for these files) to add the following, this program will run whenever you start Cygwin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;# ssh-pageant
eval $(/usr/bin/ssh-pageant -r -a &amp;quot;/tmp/.ssh-pageant-$USERNAME&amp;quot;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Cygwin running now with the loaded private keys from Pageant, you will be able to make secure, automated SSH connections from this shell to remote environments or other services built on top of SSH, like SFTP file transfers or pushing to git repositories.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Udemy- Ultimate Python Programming Tutorial</title>
      <link>http://andrewrgoss.com/2016/udemy--ultimate-python-programming-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>http://andrewrgoss.com/2016/udemy--ultimate-python-programming-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/post/python.png&#34; alt=&#34;Python&#34; title=&#34;Python&#34; /&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.udemy.com/certificate/UC-H1VZZXZV&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;COMPLETION CERTIFICATE&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
I&amp;rsquo;ve started using Python more for work and took this course to strengthen my knowledge around the fundamentals of the language. Previously, I had been wanting to add Python to my personal tech stack for some time as it is a powerful (and popular) all-purpose programming language. It is a high-level language, meaning it looks more like a readable, human language than a low-level language does. The user-friendly syntax makes it one of the easier languages to learn and it is also one of the most commonly-used languages for analytics, data mining, and data science.
&lt;hr&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;course-progress:b609afaabbef53e4f3d69f90af30ad86&#34;&gt;Course Progress&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;progress max=&#34;1.0&#34; value=&#34;1.0&#34;&gt;&lt;/progress&gt;

&lt;p&gt;100% - completed 7/18/16.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/andrewrgoss/udemy-ultimate-python&#34; class=&#34;btn&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;View my code on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SSH With Git Bash and TortoiseGit for Windows</title>
      <link>http://andrewrgoss.com/2016/ssh-with-git-bash-and-tortoisegit-for-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>http://andrewrgoss.com/2016/ssh-with-git-bash-and-tortoisegit-for-windows/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://git-scm.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/post/git_windows.png&#34; alt=&#34;Git for Windows&#34; title=&#34;Git for Windows&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;ve ever written code of any kind for professional and personal purposes, you&amp;rsquo;ve likely come across the concept of Source Control Management (SCM). When I first became a developer, I used Subversion as my SCM tool but have since switched to the more popular &lt;a href=&#34;https://git-scm.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Git&lt;/a&gt;. I use git to commit the latest versions of code in both Linux and Windows environments, but I&amp;rsquo;m going to focus on Windows in this post as this is the operating system for my personal computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Git itself is strictly a command-line tool and in setting up my Windows machine, I wanted the ability to make passwordless commits via bash commands or through my favorite git GUI tool, &lt;a href=&#34;https://git-scm.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;TortoiseGit&lt;/a&gt;. Why passwordless? It&amp;rsquo;s gets quite annoying having to enter your Github credentials every single time you push repository changes. Through the use of SSH keys, there is a secure way of doing this that allows Git Bash (or &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cygwin.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Cygwin&lt;/a&gt;) and TortoiseGit to play nice together. I didn&amp;rsquo;t find any good current documentation for this and had to mess around a bit to get the setup I now use, hence the reason for this post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-1:ca600a9d3dfcf61b6d7740c7d2519dbe&#34;&gt;Step 1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Download the latest version of &lt;a href=&#34;https://git-scm.com/download/win&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Git for Windows&lt;/a&gt; and install it. I would recommend you use most of the default settings, including running Git from the Windows Command Prompt so you can use Cygwin as your command-line tool if you prefer it over Git Bash, which comes with this download.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/post/installing_git.png&#34; alt=&#34;Installing Git&#34; title=&#34;Installing Git&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-2:ca600a9d3dfcf61b6d7740c7d2519dbe&#34;&gt;Step 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Download the latest version of &lt;a href=&#34;https://tortoisegit.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;TortoiseGit&lt;/a&gt; and install it. There are no special steps to follow here, just keep hitting &amp;lsquo;next&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-3:ca600a9d3dfcf61b6d7740c7d2519dbe&#34;&gt;Step 3&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Generate an SSH key for your Github account following these &lt;a href=&#34;https://help.github.com/articles/generating-an-ssh-key&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;instructions&lt;/a&gt;. At the end, be sure to test your SSH connection:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;$ ssh -T git@github.com
# Attempts to ssh to GitHub
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you did everything correctly here, two files should now exist in a .ssh folder of your home directory (for Windows this will be C:\Users\&lt;em&gt;username&lt;/em&gt;\.ssh). By the default they will be named id_rsa (the private SSH key) and id_rsa.pub (the public SSH key). If you have Microsoft Publisher installed on your computer, it will think the public key is a publisher file (because of the .pub extension). Use &amp;lsquo;open with&amp;rsquo; to view this key in a text editor tool like &lt;a href=&#34;https://notepad-plus-plus.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Notepad++&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-4:ca600a9d3dfcf61b6d7740c7d2519dbe&#34;&gt;Step 4&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TortoiseGit uses a PuTTY private key file format, so you will need to generate a private key in this format using the private key you generated following the steps from Github. Search your programs and files for PuTTygen, which should have been installed with TortoiseGit. Open this program and go to Conversions &amp;gt; Import key.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Browse to the private key file you generated via &lt;code&gt;ssh-keygen&lt;/code&gt; (see step 4) and import this into PuTTygen. Click the &amp;lsquo;Save private key&amp;rsquo; button after you have imported your private SSH key to save it in PuTTY private key file format (.ppk). You will want to save it to the same location as your other keys (the .ssh folder of your home directory, C:\Users\&lt;em&gt;username&lt;/em&gt;\.ssh).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/post/putty_gen.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;PuTTY Key Generator&#34; title=&#34;PuTTY Key Generator&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/post/ssh_keys.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;SSH Keys&#34; title=&#34;SSH Keys&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-5:ca600a9d3dfcf61b6d7740c7d2519dbe&#34;&gt;Step 5&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In your Github repository, select &amp;lsquo;Clone with SSH&amp;rsquo; and copy the URL path to the clipboard (make sure it starts with &lt;code&gt;git@github.com&lt;/code&gt;). Use TortoiseGit to to clone a copy of your Github repository to your local machine (right click in the directory, then select Git Clone&amp;hellip;). Paste the copied URL path into TortoiseGit. Check &amp;lsquo;Load Putty Key&amp;rsquo; and browse to the .ppk file you created in Step 5.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/post/tortoisegit_clone.png&#34; alt=&#34;TortoiseGit Clone&#34; title=&#34;TortoiseGit Clone&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hit &amp;lsquo;OK&amp;rsquo; and that&amp;rsquo;s it! You now have a SSH repository on your Windows machine that you can push passwordless changes with using either the TortoiseGit GUI or the command line with Git Bash (or Cygwin). I tend to use TortoiseGit for one-off commits and automated deployment scripts through the command line for repositories I am frequently making changes to. Regardless of approach, it is nice to have TortoiseGit installed on your Windows machine to easily visually identify any uncommitted changes for a repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/post/tortoisegit_repo.png&#34; alt=&#34;TortoiseGit Repo&#34; title=&#34;TortoiseGit Repo&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;andgoss@MYCOMPUTER MINGW64 /C/Github_AG/mssql-library (master)
# Push source and build repos.
git push origin master
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Data Science Conference East</title>
      <link>http://andrewrgoss.com/2016/open-data-science-conference-east/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>http://andrewrgoss.com/2016/open-data-science-conference-east/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.odsc.com/boston&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/post/odsc.png&#34; alt=&#34;Open Data Science Conference&#34; title=&#34;Open Data Science Conference&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In May 2016 I attended my first &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.odsc.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Open Data Science Conference&lt;/a&gt; in Boston. There were some 3,000+ data science practioners that came together at the Boston Convention &amp;amp; Exhibition Center to share ideas about this rapidly changing discipline. The following topics were covered throughout the conference:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deep Learning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Machine Learning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Predictive Analytics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;R&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Julia&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hadoop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spark&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scikit-learn&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Natural Language Processing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I attended sessions on popular data science statistical models and using Python for data science, where we worked through &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/brianbelljr/fantasy_football/blob/master/football.ipynb&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this example&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The workshop materials from the conference are available on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.opendatascience.com/category/conferences&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;opendatascience.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analytic Disciplines Compared to Data Science</title>
      <link>http://andrewrgoss.com/2016/analytic-disciplines-compared-to-data-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>http://andrewrgoss.com/2016/analytic-disciplines-compared-to-data-science/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Came across an excellent article on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.datasciencecentral.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Data Science Central&lt;/a&gt; that digs into the differences between data science, data mining, machine learning, statistics, operations research, and so on. The author compares several analytic disciplines that overlap to explain the differences and common denominators. Typical job titles, types of analyses, and industries traditionally attached to each discipline are also detailed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.datasciencecentral.com/profiles/blogs/17-analytic-disciplines-compared&#34; class=&#34;btn&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;*Source: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.datasciencecentral.com/profiles/blogs/17-analytic-disciplines-compared&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Data Science Central&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWSome Day Boston</title>
      <link>http://andrewrgoss.com/2016/awsome-day-boston/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>http://andrewrgoss.com/2016/awsome-day-boston/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/post/awsome_day.png&#34; alt=&#34;AWSome Day&#34; title=&#34;AWSome Day&#34; /&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In March 2016 I joined Amazon Web Services for an all-day training event at the Westin Copley Place in Boston. The workshop provided a step-by-step introduction to the core AWS services for compute, storage, database and networking. AWS technical experts explained key features and use cases, shared best practices, and walked through technical demos. We specifically covered the following topics:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Module 1&lt;/b&gt;: AWS Introduction and History&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Module 2&lt;/b&gt;: Infrastructure Services: Amazon EC2, Amazon S3, Amazon EBS, and Amazon VPC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Module 3&lt;/b&gt;: Security, Identity, and Access Management: IAM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Module 4&lt;/b&gt;: Databases: Amazon DynamoDB and Amazon RDS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Module 5&lt;/b&gt;: AWS Elasticity and Management Tools: Auto Scaling, Elastic Load Balancing, Amazon CloudWatch, and AWS Trusted Advisor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The day was a great for networking, learning more about cloud computing (from the clear market leader in this space) and how to get started on AWS Cloud. It is particularly valuable as some of my working environment is being shifted to Amazon&amp;rsquo;s data warehouse solution, &lt;a href=&#34;https://aws.amazon.com/redshift&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Amazon Redshift&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The slides from this event can be viewed &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.slideshare.net/secret/fcDgOrIt5Eldb6&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Caleb Doxsey- An Introduction to Programming in Go</title>
      <link>http://andrewrgoss.com/2016/caleb-doxsey--an-introduction-to-programming-in-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>http://andrewrgoss.com/2016/caleb-doxsey--an-introduction-to-programming-in-go/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/post/golang_gopher.png&#34; alt=&#34;Golang Gopher&#34; title=&#34;Golang Gopher&#34; /&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.golang-book.com/books/intro&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;BOOK LINK&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://golang.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Go (Golang)&lt;/a&gt; is an open source programming language that makes it easy to build simple, reliable, and efficient software. I first started using Go through my work at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.digitaslbi.com/us&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;DigitasLBi&lt;/a&gt;. My department adopted this language as one of our tech stacks for the following reasons:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It’s open source (i.e. free) and intended to be simple yet expressive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It’s intended to be a good middleware layer to provide for both quick one-off applications as well as large collaborative code bases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a static simple language, which allows for static analysis tooling and fast compilation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It can easily be compiled across multiple platforms, which is important for us since we host several different commercial and open source operating systems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s based around composition instead of OOP inheritance, which avoids a whole class of issues. There&amp;rsquo;s no type casting hell. Things are either a type or not.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Objects and functionality can easily be combined. Structs provide simple blue-prints. Interfaces provide a lightweight polymorphism without complicating things too much.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Concurrency is built in through Go routines and channels, which are a simple and efficient means to run multiple executions at once.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My aim in reading this book and completing the accompanying exercises was to gain a thorough understanding on the fundamentals of the Go programming language.
&lt;hr&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;book-progress:c587c0792512b02996a2b4d2d5abf088&#34;&gt;Book Progress&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;progress max=&#34;1.0&#34; value=&#34;1.0&#34;&gt;&lt;/progress&gt;

&lt;p&gt;100% - completed 01/27/16.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/andrewrgoss/golang-book&#34; class=&#34;btn&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;View my code on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Udemy- Programming for Beginners in C#</title>
      <link>http://andrewrgoss.com/2015/udemy--programming-for-beginners-in-c/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>http://andrewrgoss.com/2015/udemy--programming-for-beginners-in-c/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/post/csharp.png&#34; alt=&#34;C#&#34; title=&#34;C#&#34; /&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.udemy.com/certificate/UC-TT5IFIPW&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;COMPLETION CERTIFICATE&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on Windows servers throughout my career, which initially got me started with this language. Learning some of the Base Class Library (BCL) of the Microsoft .NET Framework and using these classes through C# has helped me automate various tasks within these environments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My goal in taking this course was to strengthen my knowledge around the fundamentals of C# programming (and objected-oriented programming in general) and to get more practice.
&lt;hr&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;course-progress:0419b73c29db8b0a8014c550c35f1f69&#34;&gt;Course Progress&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;progress max=&#34;1.0&#34; value=&#34;1.0&#34;&gt;&lt;/progress&gt;

&lt;p&gt;100% - completed 11/28/15.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/andrewrgoss/udemy-beginning-csharp&#34; class=&#34;btn&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;View my code on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Switched from Wordpress to Hugo</title>
      <link>http://andrewrgoss.com/2015/why-i-switched-from-wordpress-to-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>http://andrewrgoss.com/2015/why-i-switched-from-wordpress-to-hugo/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/post/hugo.png&#34; alt=&#34;Hugo&#34; title=&#34;Hugo&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
For a long time I&amp;rsquo;ve believed in the importance of having a blog but have struggled to keep one going. I started out using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.blogger.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Blogger&lt;/a&gt; back in the day and most recently was using &lt;a href=&#34;https://wordpress.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wordpress&lt;/a&gt;. But there were features about these blogging platforms that consistently bugged me. Fortunately for me, while I was learning the &lt;a href=&#34;http://golang.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Go&lt;/a&gt; programming language I stumbled across &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;, a static site generator written in this language. I started experimenting with Hugo and instantly loved it. I experimented with several different themes and eventually migrated my blog from Wordpress to Hugo. Here are the features I like most about Hugo and how I compare it to Wordpress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;live-previews:f3941651fa35be8fa9dd1215cdae54e4&#34;&gt;Live Previews&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every time I prepared a post on Wordpress with text and articles I would have to publish it to see how it looks within the context of the overall site. Yes- it&amp;rsquo;s true that you can save content in draft mode and only make it live after proof-reading. But this was in a different screen - the admin section. I much prefer to see a live preview of the full site as I work. When I discovered Hugo and started experimenting with it, I fell in love with the &lt;code&gt;hugo server&lt;/code&gt; command. This is an inbuilt server that can serve up your website content so you can instantly preview changes as part of the full site the second you save them. There is a way to render drafts too with the &lt;code&gt;--buildDrafts&lt;/code&gt; parameter but I prefer just running the production version knowing that since my site is hosted on &lt;a href=&#34;https://pages.github.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt;, nothing will happen until I commit and push the changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;Change detected, rebuilding site
2016-04-25 17:17 -0400
0 draft content
0 future content
10 pages created
13 paginator pages created
9 tags created
in 96 ms
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;markdown-support:f3941651fa35be8fa9dd1215cdae54e4&#34;&gt;Markdown Support&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bash script code above is nicely formatted right? The fact that Hugo supports &lt;a href=&#34;https://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Markdown&lt;/a&gt; as well as straight-up HTML is another feature I greatly enjoy. For anyone unfamiliar with Markdown, it is a plain text formatting syntax that gets converted to HTML. Using Markdown makes it easier and much quicker to write technical posts as it supports syntax highlighting for a ton of languages. I knew that some of my more technical posts needed to contain code snippets but Wordpress isn&amp;rsquo;t too-friendly for this working in a WYSIWYG editor. Simply copying and pasting this code within a post doesn&amp;rsquo;t work as it removes all of the syntax highlighting and formatting from my favorite IDE (interactive development environment) tools. Yes, there are plugins to support this - but I&amp;rsquo;m comfortable working in Markdown and it&amp;rsquo;s nice to be able to write up content offline if needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;free-hosting-with-github-pages:f3941651fa35be8fa9dd1215cdae54e4&#34;&gt;Free Hosting With Github Pages&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Wordpress I used &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bluehost.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;BlueHost&lt;/a&gt; as my web host, as many do with their Wordpress blogs. It is easy to use and cheap (I was paying $2.99 a month). Moreover, it has lots of features designed specifically for Wordpress usage. The setup was easy enough using a one-click install from the hosting dashboard and then being able to install plugins, themes, and updates, all from the Wordpress admin. But I had to login through that dashboard every time to access my Wordpress site. And while my monthly cost was small, I much prefer free. (who doesn&amp;rsquo;t?)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;custom-themes:f3941651fa35be8fa9dd1215cdae54e4&#34;&gt;Custom Themes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I knew I wanted a minimalistic, responsive site that is easy to navigate without too much scrolling. I&amp;rsquo;m not going to deny that Hugo has nowhere near the numbers of themes that Wordpress does. On Wordpress I searched through probably hundreds of different themes before settling on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.s5themes.com/theme/focused&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Focused&lt;/a&gt;. Hugo is continuing to add more themes to its library but searching through them was a lot easier since they all live on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hugo website&lt;/a&gt;. With Wordpress both free and paid themes are scattered across the interwebs. I also found the source code much easier to obtain for the Hugo themes since each one is free and links to its respective Github repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;rendering-speed:f3941651fa35be8fa9dd1215cdae54e4&#34;&gt;Rendering Speed&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, my site rendered very slowly with Wordpress/BlueHost. I’m already a fan and user of the Go language, and so in following a number of the Go social communities, I discovered Hugo. One of the most popular aspects of Go is speed as it is a langauge with subroutines baked in making it easy to execute concurrent processes. The Hugo static site generator is written in Go. A static site generator is an application that can take content in some original description (markdown in the case of Hugo) and render final content by applying rules. This final content can then be hosted anywhere, without the need for server-side runtime support such as Python/PHP/Go/Node/etc. This is because it does not require server-side processing to handle rendering pages on the fly. This makes the site very portable and simple to deploy and can be served out of aggressive caching.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;disadvantages:f3941651fa35be8fa9dd1215cdae54e4&#34;&gt;Disadvantages&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the major disadvantages of Hugo, or any static site generator for that matter, is integrating search. You either need some &lt;a href=&#34;http://discuss.gohugo.io/t/how-are-you-implementing-site-search/986/14&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;JavaScript magic&lt;/a&gt; or a 3rd party search provider like &lt;a href=&#34;Google Custom Search Engine&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Google Custom Search Engine&lt;/a&gt;, which is what I went for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other dynamic part of an ordinary blog is the comment section. Again, the easiest way to fix this is relying on a 3rd party comments plugin like &lt;a href=&#34;https://disqus.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Disqus&lt;/a&gt;. Hugo offers &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/extras/comments&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;support&lt;/a&gt; for this and makes it fairly simple to implement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though Hugo does not come with search or a comments section as built-in features, I didn&amp;rsquo;t take issue with this as I quickly found ways to integrate them anyways. So to me, these two disadvantages are easily outweighed by the advantages of a static website. Your website will survive &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Slashdot_effect&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;slashdotting&lt;/a&gt; and the only required maintenance is literally making sure your web server stays online (and I think I&amp;rsquo;m in pretty good shape with Github).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion:f3941651fa35be8fa9dd1215cdae54e4&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wordpress is the most popular content management system (CMS) for a reason. There are countless commercial websites and personal blogs powered by Wordpress along with thousands of customizable plugins. You don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily have to know how to program to build a beautiful-looking Wordpress site. But what you probably didn&amp;rsquo;t know is that the typical CMS driven website works by building each page on-demand, fetching content from a database and running it through a template engine. This means each page is assembled from templates and content on each request to the server. However, this is usually completely unnecessary overhead and only adds complexity, performance problems and security issues. After all, most websites only change when the content authors or their design team makes changes. As the sole proprieter of andrewrgoss.com, this was the case for me and my pages were often quite slow in loading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you are someone who is comfortable coding and looking to publish a personal website/blog that is lightning-quick, highly customizable and free (open-source), Hugo may be a good choice for you. For me it has also been a great way to practice front-end development as most of my time is spent on the back-end. And if you ever get stuck, there is a great &lt;a href=&#34;https://discuss.gohugo.io&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hugo community&lt;/a&gt; for Q&amp;amp;A support.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>