<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Analytics on Data Engineer, Consultant, BI Developer in MarTech</title>
    <link>http://andrewrgoss.com/tags/analytics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Analytics on Data Engineer, Consultant, BI Developer in MarTech</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://andrewrgoss.com/tags/analytics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Stages of the Analytics Life Cycle</title>
      <link>http://andrewrgoss.com/2016/stages-of-the-analytics-life-cycle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>http://andrewrgoss.com/2016/stages-of-the-analytics-life-cycle/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Across industries, the applied use of data to inform business decisions has become a foundational (arguably critical) element of business. The end goal is to ultimately derive actionable insights from vast amounts of data being collected but it takes a series of activities/tasks to arrive at this juncture. Here is a description of each stage of the analytics life cycle:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Data Acquisition&lt;/b&gt; – This may involve scraping data, interfacing with APIs, querying relational and non-relational databases, or defining strategy in relation to what data to pursue.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Data Cleaning/Transformation&lt;/b&gt; – This may involve parsing and aggregating messy, incomplete, and unstructured data sources to produce datasets that can be used in analytics and/or predictive modeling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Analytics&lt;/b&gt; – This involves statistical and machine learning-based modeling in order to understand, describe, or predict patterns in the data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Prescribing Actions&lt;/b&gt; – This involves interpreting analytical results through the lens of business priorities, and using data-driven insights to inform strategy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Programming/Automation&lt;/b&gt; – In many cases, data scientists are responsible for creating libraries and utilities to operationalize or simplify various stages of this process. Often, they will contribute production-level code for a firm’s data products.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;*Source: Burtch Works&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;big-data-analytics-lifecycle:fabfcdc15793a32766e038f5387cbc68&#34;&gt;Big Data Analytics Lifecycle&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Big Data analysis differs from traditional data analysis primarily due to the volume, velocity, and variety of characteristics for the data being processed. This is a helpful overview I found on the high-level steps involved with acquiring, processing, analyzing, and repurposing data with the end goal of performing Big Data analysis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.informit.com/content/images/chap3_9780134291079/elementLinks/03fig06.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;*Source: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.informit.com/articles/article.aspx?p=2473128&amp;seqNum=11&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;InformIT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analytic Disciplines Compared to Data Science</title>
      <link>http://andrewrgoss.com/2016/analytic-disciplines-compared-to-data-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>http://andrewrgoss.com/2016/analytic-disciplines-compared-to-data-science/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Came across an excellent article on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.datasciencecentral.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Data Science Central&lt;/a&gt; that digs into the differences between data science, data mining, machine learning, statistics, operations research, and so on. The author compares several analytic disciplines that overlap to explain the differences and common denominators. Typical job titles, types of analyses, and industries traditionally attached to each discipline are also detailed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.datasciencecentral.com/profiles/blogs/17-analytic-disciplines-compared&#34; class=&#34;btn&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;*Source: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.datasciencecentral.com/profiles/blogs/17-analytic-disciplines-compared&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Data Science Central&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>